Victory Jesutofunmi Ikuomola

Iwaya, Yaba, Lagos victoryikuomola@gmail.com 07035507270

Summary

I am a software engineer with 3 years of professional work experience. I build web applications, web services and application programming interfaces that are secure, optimal and meet their demands.

With a primary Focus on web application and API development, I have built and maintained digital fintech and edtech solutions and products that are currently in use (Social Lender, E - LMS and bincomDevCenter app), I have also worked as a freelance developer on cross-platform mobile application projects, and web application projects.

I am a graduate of Computer science and information technology.

Over the years, the academic knowledge and work experience I have gained has helped improve my efficiency in the development of user-centric web and mobile applications mainly using PHP(Laravel, slim and Yii frameworks) JavaScript (Node and express frameworks) and flutter with Dart.

Links to my GitHub repository and LinkedIn profile can be found below.

Github: https://github.com/codewithot

Linkedin: https://www.linkedin.com/in/victory-ikuomola-992133118/

Skills

- PHP
- Laravel
- Yii2 framework
- · Slim framework
- · Symphony
- JavaScript
- · NodeJS
- SQL
- git
- Python
- · Django Framework
- Flask
- Wordpress
- Flutter & Dart for Cross-platform mobile app development (iOS & android)

Work Experience

Trustvas Limited

Intermediate Software Engineer • Lagos, Nigeria

03/2023 - Present

- · Performed constructive development and code reviews while mentoring junior developers
- Translated software requirements into workable programming code and built scalable web applications that solve a variety of problems for our clients.

 Participated in code design and reviews to ensure the delivery of quality products to clients and enhance junior developers' skillset.

Bincom ICT solutions

Team Lead, Backend Team · Lagos, Nigeria

03/2023 - Present

- Mentored and reviewed team members tasks and projects.
- Using project management tools such as Jira, and Azure devops I monitored and managed various projects and tasks developed by team members while ensuring they are delivered within their timeline.
- Set clear team goals and motivated team members to achieve these goals
- Created an inspiring team environment with an open communication culture.
- Delegated task to team members and set deadlines.
- Monitored team performance and report on metrics.
- Supervised day to day operations and provided coaching and assitance.
- Encouraged creativity and organized team building activities.

Bincom ICT Solutions

Junior Software Engineer • Yaba, Lagos

12/2022 - 03/2023

- · Maintained the bincom dev center app, a web application built on Laravel, and fixed bugs.
- Maintained SocialLender, a web application built on yii2, and fixed bugs.
- Built and maintained landing pages using WordPress CMS.

Trustvas limited

Software Developer Intern • Lagos, Nigeria

05/2022 - 03/2023

- · Code refactoring of PushBankTransfer service.
- Code refactoring of PushBillPayment service.
- Code refactoring of the 2018 wallet service.
- Maintenance of the client portal.
- Integration of the 2018 wallet with MTN madapi.
- Integration of the push bank transfer service with Zenith Bank for Z-cash.
- Rebuilt the billing endpoint for 2018 wallet.

Bincom ICT Solutions

Software Developer Intern • Yaba, Lagos

08/2020 - 05/2021

- Responsible for maintenance of the Social lender API.
- Responsible for building and integrating new algorithms to improve the Social lender credit scoring algorithm.
- Responsible for Writing and working on new machine learning algorithms.
- Responsible for writing complex SQL queries to fetch from and save data to the database.
- · Set up a development server using AWS.
- Responsible for setting up Heroku to scale and contain and deploy web apps built.
- Responsible for guiding intern developers on proper code documentation.
- · Responsible for testing codes in preparation for staging.

Education

Bowen University

Computer science and information technology • Iwo, Osun

11/2021

Languages

English, Yoruba